Subha Chandra (Holding Job Seeker Visa)

Java/J2EE Software Engineer

I have 10.1 years of functional and technical experience in design, development, testing and implementation of Java web applications. I am having proficiency at grasping new technical concepts quickly and utilizing same in a productive manner. Having excellent analytical & communication skills.



+91 7975742893



in https://www.linkedin.com/in/jsubhachandra/

in https://www.linkedi

KEY SKILLS

```
• Java • Spring • Microservices • Product Development • CICD
• AWS • Agile • SOAP/REST • Backend • Mentoring • Jenkins • Problem Solving
```

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

Quest Global - SVOD



June 2019 to Present Bangalore, India

Generating the reports using measures of streaming video content played on TV Channels.

Responsibilities

- Having primary role of application design, build and deployment.
- Ability to work in an agile environment.
- Active interaction with client for requirement gathering & analysis and upcoming plans.
- Created REST services to trigger report generation.
- Add swagger UI to support better project documentation and reusability.
- To bring the DevOps mind-set within the team and within the organisation.
- Delivering best practices and code quality to the team.

Tech stack: Java 11, Spring Boot, Micro Services, AWS, Hibernate, SQL, Oracle 11g, REST, Jenkins, Apache Kafka JUnit, Mockito, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, Maven, GIT, DevOps.

Java Developer

Sonata Software



June 2017 to April 2019 Bangalore, India

Implemented a customer field scheduling to enable customers to schedule specific time slots for service.

Responsibilities

- Writing REST/SOAP services to book the slots and deployed the project using Jenkins.
- Finding new tool and technologies and doing proof of concept for those.
- Saved Application response time.

Tech stack: Java 8, Spring Boot, Micro Services, AWS, Hibernate, JavaScript, SQL, Oracle 11g, Junit, HTML, GIT

Software Engineer

Capgemini-Innovation



January 2012- May 2017 **Bangalore**, India

Responsible for implementing innovation solutions and applying gamification techniques to the products.

Responsibilities

- Bring innovative design, web development ideas to team.
- Worked as a Full stack developer to build, maintain and manage platforms.
- Developed application using spring boot and RESTful API's.

Tech stack: Java 8, Spring Boot, Micro Services, AWS, Hibernate, JavaScript, SQL, Oracle 11g, Junit, HTML, GIT

Software Engineer

Teamware Solutions



May 2011 - December 2011 Bangalore, India

Involved migration of existing J2ee application from WebLogic server to JBoss server.

Responsibilities

- Application development using Java.
- Did legacy code refactoring.
- Migrated the Ant build system to Maven.

Tech stack: Java, Spring MVC, Servlets, JDBC, Hibernate, MYSQL, Ant, Eclipse, Maven, JBoss.

Software Analyst

Honeywell Technologies



April 2010 - April 2011 Bangalore, India

Aerospace BU management Developed to Increase Predictability, Secure Supply, Reduce Raw Material Costs.

Responsibilities

- Application development using Java.
- Developing the utility classes.
- Involved for developing the DAO, Service, Controller classes.

Tech stack: Java, Spring MVC, Servlets, JDBC, Hibernate, MYSQL, Ant, Eclipse, Maven, JBoss.

TECHNICAL COMPITENCIES

Programming Java 8 & 11, Java EE, SQL, Python (Scripting)

Frameworks Spring, Spring Boot, Micro Services, AWS, Hibernate, JDBC, Spring Template, JPA **CICD** Jenkins, Maven, Docker, Sonar, JaCoCo, Artifactory, OpenShift, Ansible, Ant

API Swagger, Postman, Jasper Reports

Web Angular JS, jQuery, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Ajax, JSP, JSF, HTML5, CSS

Architectures REST, SOAP, AWS, SOA, Apache CXF, Microservices

Servers WebLogic 12c, Tomcat, Jetty, JBoss (Wildfly)

Database MySQL, MongoDB, Oracle 11g, Cassandra and NoSQL

Message Brokers Apache Kafka, Active MQ, JMS, IBM MQ

Tools IntelliJ, Eclipse, Git, Jira, Bitbucket, JMeter, TOAD, SQL Developer, JMeter, SOAP UI

CERTIFICATIONS & ACHIVEMENTS

- Java and Spring Framework
- Object Oriented Programming in Java
- AWS Certified Developer
- AWS Concepts
- Team of The Quarter for Outstanding Contribution

LANGUAGES

English-fluent, German-elementary

EDUCATION

Master's Degree – Computer Science, Information Technology https://www.skuniversity.org

BSC- Bachelor's Degree https://www.svuniversity.edu.in

Authorised to work in

Germany (Having a Job Seeker Visa), India